"The Strongest Mega Evolution"...
...is a story about Mega Evolution.
Alan, the assistant of Mega Evolution researcher Professor Platane,
set off in search of Mega Stones.
However, he couldn't attain the desired results.
Just then, someone reached out his hand to Alan:
Fleur-de-lis, who plans to use Mega Evolution energy for peaceful purposes.
Alan was entrusted a Mega Stone on the condition that he works with him on this plan.
They then went to the Houen region,
where their first course of action was to successfully retrieve...
...the legendary megalith related to Mega Evolution energy.
However, a single seed of doubt was planted in Alan.
That seed was the presence of the novice Trainer Manon, with whom he had been traveling since their coincidental meeting.
The Strongest Mega Evolution ~Act IV~
While watching anime, make sure not to sit too close to the screen and that the room is well lit.
Hey, did you watch the news about Kanazumi Bay?
I sure did. You mean the legendary Pokémon, right?
Yo, Manon-kun. It's been a while.
Has something happened?
Professor, uh...
You know a Trainer named Alan, right?
We traveled with him.
With Alan?
Hello, Professor.
Daigo-san...
Isn't it?
Manon-kun, Alan-kun and I have been through some things together.
Listen, Alan.
Yes.
If you want to call yourself the strongest, win.
I know.
You say you haven't fought enough...
Correct.
I'm still far from being the strongest.
Why are you in such a hurry?
I'm not in a hurry!
Very well, then.
Let me gather ten Mega Evolution users.
Thank you very much.
However...
...if you get defeated just once,
I'll have you return the Mega Stone and the Key Stone to me.
I don't need weaklings.
"If you want to fulfill your wish..."
"...become the greatest."
Does it look like he'll win?
Pachira, huh?
Who knows?
I...
...won't lose!
This is to protect what's important to me...!
You're so unlucky...
...that I'm your first opponent.
Let's begin.
Continue the fight even if it means going beyond your limits.
Let's do this, Lizardon!
Fushigibana, come on!
Why are you pushing him this far?
You'll know when you fight him.
If he makes it to the end at all, that is.
Mega evolve!
Respond to my heart,
Key Stone!
Surpass evolution!
Mega evolve!
Let's go, Lizardon!
Flamethrower!
Now that it's mega evolved, Fire won't work on this guy!
Now! Venoshock!
Poison?
I wonder if it's over already.
Director.
Some guests are here for you.
Got it.
Whoa, so huge!
I wonder what this huge ball is.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Fleur-de-lis-san!
I'm glad to see you.
Excuse me, but is Alan here?
He sure is.
He's battling.
May I go watch?
Let me show the way.
All right!
What about you, Daigo-san?
I'll catch up with you later.
Got it!
This is about the megalith, isn't it?
Lizardon!
Never mind her! Worry about yourself!
Swing it around!
Get up, Lizardon!
You still wanna continue...?
In that case, use Seed Bomb!
Dragon Claw!
Fushigibana!
He won!
Here's a Momon Berry.
Cure the poison.
Hey, Alan!
There's no time to rest.
I'm rather impatient, you see.
I intend to squash you. Be prepared.
Go, Foodin!
Change!
Mega evolve!
Come on, this is only the second one!
Focus your mind!
Psycho Cut!
Dragon Claw!
As you can see, we've taken measures to ensure the energy doesn't leak out.
This is to prevent what took place the other day from happening again.
Flamethrower!
Bossgodora!
Good job lasting this long.
Once we've managed ten victories, there's something I've been thinking about.
Alan!
What are you doing here?
What do you mean, "what"?
Never mind that. Is it true that that you're staking your Key Stone and Mega Stone in the battles?
Yeah.
Why would you...?
It's none of your business.
Non, non. Don't get in the way.
Hey, what about our journey?
You just tagged along without asking...
When you're there with us, Hari-san and I can become stronger too!
Let's keep traveling together!
We can't!
Why not?!
If you stay with me, you'll just get into danger again.
But with you by our side, we can make it through!
Don't rely on me any more.
Alan!
Don't you get it?
I can't become stronger as long as you're around!
You look like you want to say something.
This is how it should be.
Hari-san...
Leave me alone for a bit.
Increase the output.
Yes.
There is a response.
Good.
Also, change the cycle of the beam.
Yes.
Zygarde is shrinking.
Change the cycle back!
Yes.
Hurry up and restore it!
Where did this guy come from?
What's the matter?
Hey, wait!
Dragon Claw!
Well done, Lizardon.
Just one more.
I'm shocked...
I can't believe you actually were able to defeat nine people.
Nice to meet you. I'm Pachira.
I shall be your final opponent.
Elite Four member...
...Pachira.
Oh my, you know me?
That makes me happy.
Over here.
Huh? Where's Manon-kun?
I saw her standing on the battlefield for a while, but then she disappeared.
Excuse me.
You seem to have lost to Zumi-kun.
We're different from who we were back then!
I have more things to protect now.
Hellgar!
A Fire type, huh...?
Lizardon, let's show her everything we've got!
Open up the path to being the strongest!
Mega evolve!
She's worthy of being the final opponent.
Flamethrower!
Flash Fire?
That's right.
Flames are meals for this little one.
Blaze up,
Hellgar!
Mega evolve!
Flamethrower!
Fly, Lizardon!
Smog!
Reduce it to ashes with Flamethrower!
Using force, huh?
I don't dislike that.
Steel Wing!
Flick it away!
Crunch!
What?!
Lizardon!
You seem to be using Mega Evolution in your aim to become the strongest...
...but what is Mega Evolution to you?
Why are you asking me that?
I have an interest in you.
Lizardon, Flamethrower!
Won't you answer me?
I just want to be strong...
...together with Lizardon.
There are plenty of strong Pokémon.
Why does it have to be Lizardon?
I've walked this path together with Lizardon.
We've fought together...
...and aimed for the same destination together.
I believe in it.
How straightforward you are.
No wonder the director likes you.
Dark Pulse!
Charge!
Dragon Claw!
Crunch!
Flamethrower!
Wasn't that...?
Hari-san!
Hey, wait!
Hey, you!
Hari-san, what happened?
What have you done to Hari-san?!
Out of the way! We're in a hurry!
You get out of the way!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Manon-kun!
Daigo-san.
Something's wrong with Hari-san.
Lizardon!
Oh my, you seem to be tired.
I'll give you some relief.
Crunch!
Lizardon!
Go!
Blast Burn!
I can't believe its power...
Well done, Lizardon.
Thank you for the hard work, Hellgar.
You truly are a detestable Trainer.
So detestable it actually makes me like you.
Congrats on beating all ten.
Thank you very much.
Director...
Defeating Pachira is quite a feat.
You sure have shown me...
...a bond that exceeded its limits.
It means that Mega Evolution can't be achieved by Pokémon alone.
Yes.
I realized that it requires us Trainers to have a great resolve as well.
I'm grateful.
Now I can protect everything that's important to me.
Oh? And what is it that's important to you?
Director.
What?!
Manon-kun!
Professor!
Joy-san, how is Hari-san?
Its life is not in danger, but I don't know the cause of its comatose state.
No way...
Right now there's nothing I can do but watch how things develop.
How did this happen?
I don't know.
I have no idea!
We'll be keeping Harimaron at the Fleur-de-lis Foundation.
No facility is better than ours.
You're Director Fleur-de-lis, right?
It's nice to meet you, Professor.
I'll take responsibility for Harimaron and make efforts towards its recovery.
Hari-san will be all right, won't it?
It will... It will wake up for sure, won't it?
Yes. Leave it to us.
To wake up Harimaron, we need to establish the Mega Evolution energy system as soon as possible.
I'll do it.
I'll do it to save Harimaron, and to bring back Manon's smile.
Wait a second.
That's a Key Stone on your arm, right?
I can't believe you.
What do you mean?
Catching such a pure boy...
You're a bad man.
I haven't told a single lie.
Oh well.
I now know the reason you like that kid.
Wait for me, Manon.
I'll save Harimaron, no matter what!
So please show me...
...your smile once more!
Lizardon, Flamethrower!
This is a story of humans and Pokémon revolving around Mega Evolution.
Those who fight...
Those who pray...
Those who investigate...
And finally, those who change the world...
In the near future,
the bond between humanity and Pokémon will be put to the test.